AROTIBA MOTUNRAYO BLESSING

6, Agbanikanda Street, Ogba, Lagos State, Nigeria +2347035982480 | arotiba_blessing@yahoo.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A Chemical Engineer with over two years' experience in the polymer and specialty chemical industry. Experienced in scientific theories and experimental procedures with specialization in research, lab analysis, report generation, documentation and project direction. Organizational and analytical skills to evaluate and revise scientific research processes and improve accuracy and efficiency. Excellent communicator, able to interact with colleagues and clients at all levels. Fluent in English and Yoruba.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Cormart Nigeria Limited Process Chemist

Industrial Estate, Lagos State, Nigeria

March 2020-Till Date

- Developed formulations for high viscosity styrene acrylic copolymer resin used in the coatings industry as a binder.
- Achieved in research, high quality dispersant used also in the coatings industry specifically the paint sector to disperse inorganic pigments at the milling stage of the production process.
- Performed analytical tests (wet abrasion scrub test, viscosity, pH, solid content, water resistance
 test), inspections and monitoring of raw materials used in the coatings industry and finished
 products for specification compliance.

Selected accomplishment

- Successfully developed a standard formulation for low viscosity styrene-acrylic copolymer resin
 of high gloss and high solid content.
- Established through research a standard formulation for polymeric thickener used in water borne coatings as a rheological modifier.
- Efficiently executed the batch production of 600 tons of styrene-acrylic copolymer resin using Simatic Batch Software Package (Simatic PCS 7) to perform functions such as: controlling and monitoring batch processes, planning production orders and recording batches and recipe used.

Research and Development Intern (NYSC)

November 2018- March 2020

Selected accomplishment

- Served as a Technical Support for the sales department in troubleshooting product returns and also as an after sales support to ensure products are used in the right way and under the right conditions with strict adherence to the material safety data sheet.
- Established a standard operation procedure for the steam cleaning of packaging materials.
- Developed new materials and products such as paints for use in coating industry.

Masters Energy Quality Control Intern

Lagos State, Nigeria

June 2017 – November 2017

- Carried out regular audit on production lines before and after production which to a great extent reduced the extra cost incurred due to loss of materials as a result of faulty lines and/or product spillage by 7.5%.
- Prepared product and process quality reports by collecting, analysing and summarizing statistical data as well as recommending modifications where necessary.
- Performed quality checks on products by comparing analytical results (flash point, viscosity, pH, specific gravity and foaming) against standard and/or customer's specification.

Selected Accomplishment

• Formulated safety policies which significantly reduced the occurrence of accidents in the laboratory as well as the error rate of testing by 10%.

EDUCATION

University of Lagos

Akoka, Lagos State, Nigeria

Bachelor of Science in Chemical Engineering (Second Class Upper Division)

Class of 2018

CERTIFICATION AND TRAININGS

Applied Operations Management and Forecasting

Issuing Authority: Allison Credential Identifier: 1421-17057630

ISO 140001:2015- Environment Management Systems (EMS)

Issuing authority: Alison Credential Identifier: Credential ID 1428-17057630

SOFT SKILLS

- Effective in organization of ideas for logical presentation and acceptance.
- Excels in analyzing and adjusting work procedures for maximum efficiency.
- Successful at demonstrating the ability to develop, implement and enforce safety policies, standard operating procedures to ensure strict adherence to good manufacturing practices (GMP).
- Adept in interpersonal and communication skill with all levels of personnel to gain insight and avoid potential problems.
- Effective in assessing and resolving product conflicts resulting in the completion of projects before time.
- Possess strong knowledge of computer fundamentals including packages such as Microsoft office suite

INTEREST

- Process engineering
- Polymer engineering
- Environment sustainability
- Product Development

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

- Committee Member, Engineering Ladies Day, 2017.
- Volunteer Member, National Society of Chemical Engineers, Review of Curriculum, 2018.

LEADERSHIP EXPERIENCE

- Group Leader, Chemical Engineering Optimization
- · Assistant Group Leader, Chemical Engineering Design Project

Referees are available on Request